Guide to the Joseph Urban Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: New York
  - Subseries III.5: Metropolitan Opera, 1917-1933
    - La Vida Breve, March 6, 1926.:
      - --Act I.1: Gypsy, 27x34 (16x24) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 4)
      - --Act II.1: side of Manuel's house, 26x33 (17x24) cm. (Box B22, Folder 5)
      - --Act II.2: square, 27x34 (16x24) cm. (Box B22, Folder 6)
      - 6 technical drawings (Box D5, Folder 4)
      - 5 photographs of set drawings (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Don Quichotte (Don Quixote), April 3, 1926 (1927):
      First Metropolitan performance of comic opera in 5 acts, music by Jules Massenet, book by Henri Cain, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Florence Easton as Dulcinea, Feodor Chaliapin as Don Quichotte and Giuseppe DeLuca as Sancho.
      - 1 libretto (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - 5 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --I: open square, 27x35 (18x24) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 7)
      - --II: The Windmill Scene, 27x35 (18x24) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 8)
      - --III: Bandits Scene A, 27x35 (16x24) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 9)
      - --III: Bandits Scene, 28x38 (17x24) cm. (Box B22, Folder 10)
      - --V: Road in the Woods, 27x34 (16x24) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 11)
      - 7 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 12)
      - 6 photographs of set drawings (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Turandot, November 16, 1926 (1930):
      First American performance of lyric opera in 3 acts and 5 scenes, music by Giacomo Puccini, book by Giuseppe Adami and Renato Simoni, costumes by Gretl Urban and B. Brunelleschi, directed by Wilhelm Von Wymetal, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Maria Jeritza as Princess Turandot, Giacomo Lauri-Volpi as Calaf, and Giuseppe DeLuca as Ping.
      - Director's notes, von Wymetal, 20 p. (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 3 postcards, costumes Austrian production (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 3 photostats of Buddha figures (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 7 sketches and plans (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 4 property detail drawings (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 17 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 13)
      - 12 photographs of set models (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Program, 3/16/29 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Article, NY Times Magazine, 11/14/26 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Set models
    - Fidelio, January 22, 1927 (1951):
      Opera in 2 acts, music by Ludwig von Beethoven, libretto by J. Sonnleithner and F. Treitschke from the French by J. N. Bouilly, conducted for the Beethoven Centenary revival by Artur Bodanzky with Nanny Larsen-Todsen as Leonore, Rudolf Laubenthal as Florestan, George Meader as Jacquino and Michael Bohnen as Rocco.
      - 3 librettos (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Script notes & sketches, 4 p. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - 4 drawings-watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I.2: prison yard,17x24 (10x13) cm. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - --Act II.1: prison, 18x24 (10x16) cm. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - --Act II.2: castle terrace, 23x30 (17x24) cm., sig. (Box B23, Folder 1)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 14)
      - 5 photographs of set drawings. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - 2 programs, 1945-46;1950-51 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Set model
    - The King's Henchman, February 17, 1927 (1929):
      World premiere of opera in 3 acts, music by Deems Taylor, libretto by Edna St. Vincent Millay, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Lawrence Tibbett as Eadger, Edward Johnson as Aethelwold and Florence Easton as Aelfrida.
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act II: Forest, 24x30 (13x19) cm. (Box B23, Folder 2)
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and ink:
      - --Trees, 14x20 (9x12) cm. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - 2 graphed drawings of Act I, III (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - 7 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 15)
      - 1 bound piano-vocal score, inscr. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Set models
    - Violanta, November 5, 1927 (1928):
      First American performance of opera with music by E.W. Korngold, written by Hans Müller, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Maria Jeritza as Violanta, Clarence Whitehill as Simone and Walter Kirchhoff as Alfonso.
      - Libretto (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --room (not used A), 27x38 (16x26) cm.,sig. (Box B23, Folder 3)
      - --room B, 28x38 (20x22) cm. (Box B23, Folder 4)
      - 1 fireplace detail (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - 14 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 16)
      - 1 photograph of set drawing (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Hänsel und Gretel, November 5, 1927 (1948):
      Fairy opera in 3 acts, music by Engelbert Humperdinck, book by Adelheid Wette, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Editha Fleischer as Hänsel and Queena Mario as Gretel.
      - Libretto (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Set notes by Von Wymetal, 6 p. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Sketches and notes, 7 items (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Peasant's room, 26x31 (10x17) cm., sig. (Box B23, Folder 5)
      - 10 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 17)
      - 6 photographs of sets (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Set model
        [See also Boston January 27, 1912]
    - Norma, November 16, 1927 (1945):
      Opera in 4 acts and 5 scenes, music by Vincenzo Bellini, book by Felice Romani, costumes by Joseph Urban, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Rosa Ponselle as Norma, and Ezio Pinza as Oroveso.
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --II: Norma's room, 27x37 (15x20) cm. (Box B23, Folder 6)
      - --III: bedroom A, 27x37 (15x20) cm. (Box B23, Folder 7)
      - --IV.1: Rocky Pass, 27x39 (15x20) cm. (Box B23, Folder 8)
      - 2 sketches (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - 10 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 18)
      - 7 photographs of set drawings (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - 1 program, 1928-29 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Set model
    - La Rondine, March 10, 1928 (1936):
      First American performance of opera in 3 acts, music by Giacomo Puccini, costumes by Joseph Urban, conducted by Vicenzo Bellezza with Lucrezia Bori as Magda and Beniamino Gigli as Ruggero.
      - Director's notes, Von Wymetal, 17 p. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --I: Magda's salon, 28x37 (14.5x21) cm., sig. (Box B23, Folder 9)
      - --Ballroom A, 27x34 (14x21) cm. (Box B23, Folder 10)
      - --Ballroom B, 26x32 (15x21) cm. (Box B23, Folder 11)
      - --III: Park, 28x38 (15x21) cm., sig. (Box B23, Folder 12)
      - 2 set sketches (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - 12 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 19)
      - 2 photographs of set drawings (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Set model
    - Die Ägyptische Helena (Egyptian Helen), November 6, 1928 (1929):
      First American performance of opera by Richard Strauss, libretto by Hugo von Hofmannsthal, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Maria Jeritza as Helen and Rudolph Laubenthal as Menelas.
      - Piano score (Box A7, Folder 4 & 5)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --Aithra palace on island, 27x35 (15x20) cm. (Box B24, Folder 1)
      - --Enchanted tent, 27x35 (15x19) cm. (Box B24, Folder 2)
      - 14 set notes by von Wymetal (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - 10 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 20)
      - 8 photographs of sets (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Set model
    - La Campana Sommersa, November 24, 1928 (1930):
      First American performance of opera by Ottorino Respighi based on Gerhart Hauptmann's Die Versunkene Glocke, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Elizabeth Rethberg as Rautendelein, Giovanni Martinelli as Heinrich, Giuseppe DeLuca as Nickelmann and Ezio Pinza as Pastor.
      - Director's notes, Von Wymetal, 3 p. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --I, IV: Forest, 27x34 (16x19) cm., sig. (Box B24, Folder 3)
      - --II: Interior, 15x19, sig. (Box B24, Folder 4)
      - --III: Smithy, 27x34 (15x19) (Box B24, Folder 5)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 21)
      - 2 photos of set drawings (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Manon, December 22, 1928 (1952):
      Opera in 5 acts with music by Jules Massenet, words by Henri Meilhac and Philippe Gille, costumes by Joseph Urban, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Lucrezia Bori as Manon, Beniamino Gigli as Des Grieux, Leon Rothier as Comte Des Grieux and Giuseppe DeLuca as Lescaut.
      - 2 librettos (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Set notes, Von Wymetal, 5 p. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - 2 research photographs, 18c. interiors (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil, 27x34 (15x19) cm., sig.:
      - --I: Inn at Amiens (Box B24, Folder 6)
      - --II: Apartment in Paris (Box B24, Folder 7)
      - --IV: Hotel gambling room (Box B24, Folder 8)
      - --V: Road to Havre (Box B24, Folder 9)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - 15 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 22)
      - 5 photographs of set drawings (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Set model
        [See also Boston Opera, March 18, 1914]
    - Jonny Spielt Auf, January 19, 1929:
      Opera in two parts by Ernst Krenek, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Michael Bohnen as Jonny and Florence Easton as Anita.
      - 1 libretto (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - 2 reference photographs (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - 2 clippings (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - 14 sketches (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - 33 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 1)
      - 14 photographs of sets and scenes (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Set model
    - Louise, March 1, 1929 (1949):
      Opera in 4 acts and 5 scenes by Gustave Charpentier, costumes by Joseph Urban, directed by Wilhelm Von Wymetal, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Lucrezia Bori as Louise, Antonin Trantoul as Julien, and Leon Rothier as the father.
      - 1 libretto, German (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - 1 sketch of Act I & IV (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - 9 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 2)
      - 6 photographs of sets (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - 2 programs, 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Set model
        [See also Boston Opera, December 18, 1912]
    - Fra Gherardo, March 21, 1929:
      First American performance of opera by Ildebrando Pizzetti, conducted by Tullio Serafin, with Edward Johnson as Gherardo, Maria Mueller as Mariola and Ezio Pinza as the Old Man and Podesta.
      - 2 sets of script notes, German and English, 3 p. each (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - 1 drawing-watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act II: square, 22x25 cm. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - 8 sketches & details (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - 24 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 3)
      - 7 photographs of set models and sets (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Set model
    - Don Giovanni, November 29, 1929 (1953):
      Opera in 2 acts, music by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, book by Lorenzo Da Ponte, costumes by Joseph Urban, directed by Wilhelm Von Wymetal, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Ezio Pinza as Don Giovanni, Pavel Ludikar as Leporello, Leonora Corona (for Rosa Ponselle) as Donna Anna, Elisabeth Rethberg as Donna Elvira, Beniamino Gigli as Don Ottavio and Leon Rothier as the Commandante.
      - Libretto (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - 11 photographs of previous Met sets (Box A8, Folder 1)
      - Piano score (Box A8, Folder 2)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and/or pencil:
      - --Act I.1: exterior, 28x37 (15x20) cm. (Box B24, Folder 10A)
      - --Act II.5: Giovanni's room, 41x31 cm. (Box B24, Folder 10)
      - 13 set sketches (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - 34 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 4)
      - 27 photographs of set models and sets (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - 2 programs, 1929, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Set models
        [See also Boston Opera Feb. 7, 1913]
    - Luisa Miller, December 21, 1929 (1931):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera in 3 acts, music by Giuseppe Verdi, book by Salvatore Cammarano based on Schiller's Kabale und Liebe, costumes by Joseph Urban, directed by Ernst Lernt, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Giacomo Lauri-Volpi as Rodolfo, Giuseppe DeLuca as Miller and Rosa Ponselle as Luisa.
      - 22 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 5)
      - 6 sketches (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - 10 photographs of sets (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - 1 program, 1929-30 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Set model
    - Boccaccio January 2, 1931.:
      First Metropolitan performance of opera in 3 acts by Franz von Suppe, directed by Wilhelm Von Wymetal, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Maria Jeritza as Boccaccio and George Meader as Scalza.
      - Set notes, Von Wymetal, 16 p. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - 2 set details (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - 6 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 6)
      - 6 photographs of set drawings (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Set models
    - Schwanda, der Dudelsakpfeifer (Schwanda the Bagpiper), November 7, 1931 (1932):
      First American performance of Czech opera Svanda Dudák with music by Jaromir Weinberger, book by Miles Kares translated into German by Max Brod, choreographed by August Berger, directed by Hanns Niedecken-Gebhard, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Friedrich Schorr as Schwanda.
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --City Entrance, 31X39 (26X35) cm. (Box B25, Folder 1)
      - Bagpiper, pencil drawing (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - 10 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 7)
      - 6 photos of drawings & sets (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Set model
    - Donna Juanita, January 2, 1932:
      Fist Metropolitan performance of opera in 3 acts, music by Franz von Suppe, book by F. Zell and Richard Genee, costumes by Lillian Gaertner Palmedo, directed by Hans Niedecken-Gebhard, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Maria Jeritza as Donna Juanita.
      - Booklet, set notes (Box A7, Folder 6)
      - Detail sketch (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - 7 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 8)
      - 3 photographs of sets (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Program, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Set model
    - Peter Ibbetson, February 7, 1932 (1935):
      World premiere of opera in 3 acts and 8 scenes based on novel by George Du Maurier, music by Deems Taylor, libretto by Constance Collier and Deems Taylor, directed by Wilhelm von Wymetal, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Edward Johnson as Peter Ibbetson, Lucrezia Bori as Mary and Lawrence Tibbett as Colonel Ibbetson. Urban also designed the costumes for the 1933-1935 performances.
      - Libretto (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Set notes, 11p. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --II.1: Inn (Box B25, Folder 2)
      - --II.2: Garden (Box B25, Folder 3)
      - 7 set sketches and notes (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - 13 technical drawings, furniture (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - 19 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 9)
      - 1 program, 1931-1932 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Set model
      - Piano-vocal score, inscr. Deems Taylor (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - La Sonnambula, March 16, 1932 (1935):
      Opera in 3 acts, 4 scenes with music by Vincenzo Bellini, book by Felice Romani, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Lily Pons as Amina, Beniamino Gigli as Elvino and Ezio Penza as Count Rudolfo.
      - Libretto (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - 3 detail drawings (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - 13 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 10)
      - 3 photos of set drawings (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Program, 1931-1932 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Set model
    - Electra, December 3, 1932 (1962):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera in one act, music by Richard Strauss, libretto by Hugo von Hofmannsthal, costumes by Lillian Gaertner Palmedo, conducted in the first Metropolitan performance by Artur Bodanzky with Gertrude Kappel as Electra, Karin Branzell as Clytemnestra, Rudolf Laubenthal as Aigisthus and Friedrich Schorr as Orestes.
      - 2 drawings, watercolor, sig.:
      - --Set, 50x65 (36x50) cm. (Box 14-10-2, Folder 1)
      - --Set, 45x62 (28x46) cm. (Box D5, Folder 5)
      - Mounted photograph of set drawing (Box B25, Folder 4)
      - 7 technical drawings (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - 6 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 10)
      - 2 programs, 1937-1952 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Picture of set model from article (Box D5, Folder 5)
      - Set model
    - Undated or Unproduced:
      - Walküre, (1 libretto) (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Notes, 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 2 drawings of Act III, pencil (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 11)
      - 3 mounted photos of set drawings (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Set model
      - Metropolitan Opera Stage Plans (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 12)
      - Portfolio Cover, early opera plans (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Wiener Werkstätte scrapbook cover, 50x50 cm. (Box D6)
    - Librettos:
      - Josephs Legende (Legend of Joseph): --Guide to the ballet (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - --Piano score (Box A7, Folder 7)
      - Meistersinger, (2 librettos) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Merman and Mermaid, (1 libretto) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Pearl Fishers, (1 libretto) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Rheingold, (1 libretto) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Trovatore, (1 piano score) (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Villi, (1 libretto) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.6: Film, 1915-1931
    Joseph Urban was art director for William Randolph Hearst's Cosmopolitan Productions from 1919 to 1925. He also worked a year for the Fox Film Studios in 1930, drawn to the one source of income not devastatingly depleted by the Great Depression. Each film is listed by title, followed by the name of the producing studio and the releasing company, the production number and the release date. The files contain letters, contracts, reference and photo scrapbooks, drawings, photographs and articles. Some of the productions contain photographs which mark, for purposes of comparison, whether the set was lighted by the director or by Urban. Items of interest include a color key, a numbered code for how colors would photograph in black and white under studio lights, and a letter dated January 1920 which discusses whether the director or the studio should control the making of the film. The photo scrapbooks picture all the sets used for the Hearst films and show the attention to detail used for period sets as well as the imagination employed for the modern interiors. The reference scrapbooks provide an example of how Urban sourced his designs.
    - Cosmopolitan Productions, 1920-23:
      - Contract, Feb. 19, 1920, 2 p. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - 7 letters, 1920-1921, 10 p. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Articles, 1920-1923, 6 p. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - 4 photographs of color key (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Article and letter from Gurschner, 1923 (Box C5, Folder 3)
    - Strand Theater Stage Set, 1915:
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --stage and orchestra set, 24x34 cm., sig. (Box B25, Folder 4A)
      - Plan for stage set (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - 2 photographs of set (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Rivoli Theater Stage Setting, 1919:
      - 2 drawings, Watercolor and/or pencil:
      - --Mythical scene, 35x47 cm. (Box C5, Folder 4)
      - --Stage, 39x40 (37x39) cm. (Box D5, Folder 6A)
      - Set notes, 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box D5, Folder 6)
      - 2 photographs of stage setting (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - The Golem, UFA/Paramount, 1920 (US 1921):
      German film written by Paul Wegener and Henrik Galeen, set designed by Hans Polzig, directed by Paul Wegener and Carl Boese, with Paul Wegener, Albert Steinruck and Ernst Deutsch.
      - 47 photographs of scenes (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Humoresque, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #5, 1920:
      Written by Frances Marion based on the stories by Fannie Hurst, directed by Frank Borzage with Alma Rubens, Gaston Glass and Vera Gordon.
      - 2 photographs of sets & scene (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 1 photograph, Venetian Court (Box A8, Folder 3)
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - The Restless Sex, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #6, September 12, 1920:
      Romantic comedy-drama based on the Robert W. Chambers story, by Leo d'Usseau, costumes by Erté, directed by Robert Z. Leonard with Marion Davies, Carlyle Blackwell and Ralph Kellard. Norma Shearer played a bit part. Premiered at the Criterion Theater where the manager Hugo Riesenfeld composed music around the Marion Davies Waltz for the live Prologue, The Garden of Eden designed by Urban.
      - 6 technical drawings (Box 14-9-8, Folder 14)
      - 7 sketches & notes (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - 4 photographs of sets and scenes (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
        [See also Miss 1917 for drawing of Garden of Eden Prolog set]
    - The World and His Wife, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #7, 1920:
      Adapted from the play by Charles Frederic Nirdlinger which was based on the Spanish poem El Gran Galeoto by Jose Echegaray, screenplay by Frances Marion, directed by Robert G. Vignola with Alma Rubens, Montagu Love, Pedro de Córdoba and Gaston Glass.
      - 18 photographs of sets and scenes (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Heliotrope, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #8, 1920.:
      Based on Whiff of the Heliotrope by Richard Washburn Child, directed by George D. Baker with Frederick Burton.
      - 9 photographs of sets & scenes (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Inside of the Cup, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #10, 1921:
      Written by George Dubois Proctor based on a novel by Winston Churchill, directed by Albert Capellani with William Carleton and David Torrence.
      - 5 photographs of sets and scenes (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - 2 photographs of Church altar (Box A8, Folder 4 & 5)
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Passionate Pilgrim, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #11, 1921:
      Directed by Robert G. Vignola with Matt Moore and Mary Newcombe
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Buried Treasure, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #12, 1921:
      Written by F. Britten Austin, directed by George D. Baker, starring Marion Davies and Norman Kerry.
      - 14 drawings-watercolor and/or pencil:
      - --12 decorations of ship panels, paper, 11x13 cm. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - --1 pirate ship stern, 26x20 cm. (Box B25, Folder 5)
      - --Elevation of pirate ship, 74x90 cm. (Box 14-9-8, Folder 15)
      - 1 print of altar, retouched (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - 23 photographs of sets & scenes (Box 26, Folder 7 & 8)
      - 4 photographs of sets (Box A8, Folder 6-9)
      - Set model
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Straight Is the Way, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #15, 1921:
      Directed by Robert G. Vignola with Matt Moore.
      - Scrapbook #1 (Box C6)
    - Proxies, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #16, 1921:
      Story by Frank R. Adams, directed by George D. Baker with Norman Kerry and Zena Keefe.
      - 1 photograph, Set 16.9, Stairs (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Scrapbook #2 (Box C7)
    - Bride's Play, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #18, 1921:
      Story by Donn Byrne, directed by George Terwilliger, with Marion Davies and Wyndham Standing.
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Drawbridge, 17x25 (15x21) cm. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - --Servant's room, 19x22 (17x20) cm. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - --Wedding, 23x21 (19x20) cm. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - 5 plans & sketches (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Prolog, set sketch (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - 3 technical drawings, Prolog (Box 14-9-8, Folder 16)
      - 36 photographs of sets & scenes (Box 26, Folder 10 & 11)
      - 12 photographs of drawings, sets & scenes (Box A8, A9)
      - Scrapbook #2 (Box C7)
    - The Wild Goose, Cosmopolitan/Paramount, #19, 1921:
      Story by Gouveneur Morris, directed by Albert Capellani with Norman Kerry and Mary MacLaren. New York premiere at the Rialto May 1921.
      - 1 photograph of set (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - 1 photograph of set (Box A9, Folder 7)
      - Scrapbook #2 (Box C7)